Gurkiran Singh Randhawa

Full-Stack Engineer - Web Applications

Phone: (647) 679 - 0224 | Email: gukiece@gmail.com| https://www.linkedin.com/in/gurkiran4you/ Github: https://github.com/gurkiran4you & https://github.com/gurkiran

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Full-stack Developer with a **specialization in Frontend Development** and **over 10 years of experience**, worked with various teams ranging from 3 to 60 developers, built and worked on web applications from large public facing websites to customer specific apps.

KEY AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Industries Served: Healthcare, NGO, Cable Communications, Renewable Energy, Finance

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, php

Frameworks/Runtimes: NodeJS, Deno, Angular, React, AngularJS, JQuery, Lodash, jsPDF, Fresh, Tailwind

Testing Frameworks: Jasmine, Karma, Testing-library

FE/Web technologies: HTML, CSS, SCSS, HTTP, I18n, Web-socket, Browser APIs

Bundlers/Task Runners: Webpack, gulp, grunt

Databases: SQLite, SQLServer, MongoDB(Mongoose)

Other: TeamCity, Jira Workflows, CI/CD Scripts, Google Cloud, Github Actions, Docker

Side Projects:

<u>Personal Portfolio</u> <u>Side project - Unified punjab government forms</u> <u>Website for a friend - Hair Salon</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer- Web Applications

July 2019 - End of May 2024 (FT 40 hrs/week)

Circle Cardiovascular Imaging , Calgary, AB, Canada

- Full stack development of a medical reporting web application
- Responsible for Frontend architecture and localization.
- Spearheaded AngularJS to Angular migration
 - The project was in AngularJS, started migrating to Angular 9 in 2020
 - It was migrated from Angular 9 to Angular 17 in Feb 2024
- Responsible for creating UI designs patterns and implementing them as part of POC before development.
- Contributed in php to Golang migrations of various components within reporting.
- Implemented WYSIWYG report feature i.e. Edit mode, preview mode and pdf generation.
- Implemented template-driven reporting for better customizations.
- Used git and teamcity (similar to Jenkins) for CI/CD

- Shipped windows and MacOS installers as well as custom Linux installers for OEM partners GE and Siemens
- Used php, Golang, SQLServer and SQLite in BE
- Used Web-socket as well as REST services for data communication between FE and BE
- Used Python to automate scripts used in localization eg. Adding translations, compiling translations, marking them as fuzzy and finding fuzzy translations
- Did various on-calls with customers to resolve sev-1 field bugs as well as trained the marketing team on reporting.

Programmer Analyst

Feb 2016 – Nov 2018 (FT 40 hrs/week)

Marlabs Inc., Piscataway, NJ, USA

Through Marlabs, I worked for the following clients as a contractor

Web Developer Sept 2018 – Nov 2018

Fidelity Investments, Merrimack, NH, USA

- Worked on building an Onboarding portal for current and prospective hires using React
- Made the CSS modular by using SCSS features such as mixins, placeholders, functions etc.
- Used React JS to build the portal, with best practices.
- Developed Swagger API using NodeJS, as a mockup for the Java Backend team to speed up their development
- Added responsive typography throughout the app

Web Developer Feb 2018-Sep 2018

Comcast Corporation, Philadelphia, USA

- Continuing implementing agent experience app for Xfinity mobile
- This app is used by Xfinity mobile store agents to create/modify/add services/add lines to Xfinity mobile customers (Up to 5 lines)
- This project is an upgradation from an earlier outdated app which used Zendesk
- The app used latest Angular version (Angular 5 and 6) with Bootstrap , SCSS in Node environment
- Developed and maintained scalable RESTful and GraphQL APIs using Node.js, ensuring efficient data fetching and processing
- Decreased the dev build time of the app from 2 minutes to 20 seconds in webpack

Web Developer Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Envision Energy, Houston, TX, USA

- Implementing a new css version of old UI, using AngularJS
- New version included new graphs, user-friendly and more aesthetic layouts
- Implementing date-time sliders using DevExtreme DX library for time range selections in various graphs
- The graphs would come from Wind-farm data being run by Analysts

Web Developer July 2016 – July 2017

AARP, Washington DC, USA

Moving the old unresponsive components into responsive mobile-friendly web apps

- Helped in developing new proof-of-concept home page website of AARP
- Migrating some apps from AngularJS 1.2 to AngularJS 1.5
- Helped in developing new Home Page using technologies like gulp, Reactjs
- Daily content updates to match with the current home page of AARP

Jan 2012 – July 2013

Parshu Solutions, Ludhiana, INDIA

Google Web Toolkit Developer Apr 2012 – Sep 2012

Kodemuse, Gurgaon, INDIA

Systems Engineer Mar 2011 – Dec 2011

Infosys Limited, Mysore, INDIA

EDUCATION

Master's in Electrical Engineering 2015

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, USA

Bachelor's in Electronics Engineering

Punjab Technical University, Jalandhar, INDIA

INTERNSHIPS

2010

Siemens Information Systems Limited (Gurgaon, INDIA)

Punjab Communications Limited (Mohali, INDIA)